Fariba Khoshghalbvash, Data Scientist

Innovative Data Scientist. 5 years of experience in gathering, cleaning, organizing, and modeling data to provide solutions or insight for technical and non-technical personnel. Advanced understanding of statistical, algebraic, and analytical techniques. Highly organized, motivated, and diligent with significant background in Machine Learning.

Work History

12/2019-Present

Data Scientist

CTRL, LLC (startup)

- Prototyped 2 out of 3 main features of the product using statistical, algorithmic, and visualization techniques.
- Increased success rate of motion detection from %76 to %99 by designing and training a hybrid binary Autoencoder.
- Applied statistical and algebraic techniques to interpret key points from data.
- Detecting data anomalies and verifying data integrity and prepare it for analysis.
- Investigating innovative machine learning, signal processing, and statistical techniques for human activity recognition.
- Validating results and hypotheses by designing isolated experiments and calculating the appropriate metrics for evaluation.
- Participating in daily scrums and providing detailed reports and plans

05/2019-08/2019

Computer Vision R&D Intern

Atos Syntel Inc.

- Successfully localized content on parcel labels using novel regression techniques.
- Deployed image augmentation techniques and increased the sample size by 8.
- Slashed computation %33 by modifying open-source techniques such as YOLO and EAST to train on a custom dataset.
- Exploited deep convolutional neural networks for text localization and information extraction from parcel label which increased accuracy by %16.

08/2016-12/2019

Graduate Research Assistant

The University of Texas, Arlington

- Proposed a novel approach to rank top 50 biomarker genomes among ~200k.
- Designed a multimodal deep network for binary classification that outperformed old methods such as SVM, Random Forest, and Logistic Regression.
- Planned, prioritized, and executed research techniques, procedures, and tests.
- Key reviewer for multiple academic data mining conferences such as BIBM, AAAI, CSPS, and Clinical Genetics.
- Tutored students in various graduate and undergraduate analytics courses (e.g., Data Analysis & Modeling Techniques, Discrete Structures).

Education

08/2016- Master of Science: Computer Science & Engineering

12/2019 The University of Texas at Arlington - Arlington, TX, USA GPA: 3.8

09/2010- Bachelor of Science: Applied Mathematics

05/2015 Sharif University of Technologies – Tehran, Tehran, Iran

Publications

2019

ACM-BCB Integrative Feature Ranking by Applying Deep Learning on Multi Source Genomic Data CSPS The Effect of Integration Stage on Multimodal Deep Learning in Genomic Studies

2018

CSPS Integrating Heterogeneous Datasets by Using Multi-modal Deep Learning

Contact

Address

Atlanta, GA, 30328

Phone

(412) 880-9989

F-mail

fariba.khoshghalbvash@ gmail.com

inkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/fkhoshahalbvash

www

https://fariba-k.github.io/

Skills

Data preparation Data modeling Machine learning Statistical analysis Deep learning

Focused Vigilant Fast learner Multitasker

Software & Libraries



Python, NumPy, pandas, scikit-learn, matplotlib, seaborn



Keras, TensorFlow, SciPy



D

R, SQL, MATLAB, Tableau